Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Records Documenting Lacrosse
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, records documenting lacrosse
1918-1997
RU 939
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
8.25
and 1 reel.
The records consist of correspondence, newsletters, manager's files, financial records, and scrapbooks, maintained by the Yale Department of Athletics, documenting men's and women's lacrosse at Yale.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Existence and Location of Copies
Lacrosse scrapbooks are available on microfilm from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM193. 1985. 837 frames on 1 reel, 35mm.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Department of Athletics, Yale University, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, newsletters, manager's files, financial records, and scrapbooks, maintained by the Yale Department of Athletics, documenting men's and women's lacrosse at Yale.
College sports; Lacrosse; Scrapbooks; Yale University Athletic Association; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Scrapbooks of the lacrosse team, 1918-1952; Accession 2006-A-018
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1918-1923 (Box 1, Reel 1U)
    - 1924-1925 (Box 2, Reel 1U)
    - 1926-1929 (Box 2, Reel 1U)
    - 1931 (Box 4, Reel 1U)
    - 1932-1936 (Box 3, Reel 1U)
    - 1948-1952 (Box 4, Reel 1U)
- Manager's files of the lacrosse team, circa 1929-1932; Accession 2006-A-048
  - Varsity, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
  - Freshmen, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
  - Miscellanoues, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Varsity, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1932 (Box 2–4)
  - Scrapbooks, 1926, 1929 (Box 5)
- Records of the men's and women's lacrosse teams, 1938-1997; Accession 2006-A-104
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2032
  - Men's Lacrosse
    - General, 1961 (Box 1)
    - General, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Awards, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Letter of Recommendation, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - All-Ivy, 1967 (Box 1)
    - General [Yale-English Game], 1967 (Box 1)
    - General, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
    - Post Season, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Head Coach Search, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - General, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Contest Management, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - Budget, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Z, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Endowment Prospects, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Z [NCAA], 1988 (Box 1)
    - Recess, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Post Season [NCAA Championship], 1988 (Box 1)
    - Australia Trip, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 1)
    - NCAA Championship [#2 Nat'l ranking], 1990 (Box 1)
  - Women's Lacrosse
    - Articles, undated (Box 1)
    - General, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
    - Head coach for Lacrosse and Fall sport search, 1980 (Box 1)
    - General, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Post Season, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - General, 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - Budget, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Z, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - General, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - Z, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Recess, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Post Season, 1988 (Box 1)
    - General, 1988-1990 (Box 1)
    - General, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Yale Lacrosse Association
    - Robert G. Merrick, President, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
    - General, 1966, 1970-1973 (Box 2)
    - Newsletters ["Coach's Corner"], 1973-1975 (Box 2)
    - General, 1981-1985 (Box 2)
    - Endowment Proposal, 1986 (Box 2)
    - General, 1986-1990 (Box 2)
    - Yale Club Dinners, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - Phonathon, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Australia Trip, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
    - Alumni, 1988-1990 (Box 2)
  - Yale Women's Lacross Association
    - General, 1982-1986 (Box 2)
    - Phonathon, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
    - General, 1987 (Box 2)
    - General, 1988-1990 (Box 2)
  - United States Inter-Collegeite Lacrosse Association (USILA) - General, 1938 (Box 2)
    - General, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - General, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - New England Secondary School Lacrosse Association (NESSLA) - General, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
  - United States Lacrosse Coaches Association (USCLA), 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - New England Intercollegiate Lacrosse League (NEILL) - General, 1966 (Box 2)
  - The Lacrosse Foundation, 1986 (Box 2)
  - New England Intercollegiate Lacrosse Association (NEILA) - General, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
  - Men's Lacrosse Publications, 1955-1997 (Box 2)
  - Women's Lacrosse Publications, 1978-1996 (Box 2)
  - William A. R. Harkness
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Sporting goods, 1949-1951 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1957 (Box 2)
    - Players, 1950 (Box 2)
    - Newsletters, 1950 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence [Robert A. Hall, Athletic Director], 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - Games/Schedules, 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - Personal, 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - Recruiting, 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - USILA and NEILL, 1950-1951, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - Office of Sports Information, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence [Underwood Corp., NCAA, NCAB], 1951 (Box 2)
    - Coach Survey, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Nassau, Bahamas Trip, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Opponent Correspondence, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Yale Athletic Association, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 2)
    - Photo, undated (Box 2)
  - Men's Lacrosse Scorebooks, 1963-1981, 1983-1988, 1991 (Box 3)